<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Warrior on Balance Guides</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/</link><description>Recent content in Warrior on Balance Guides</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 23:35:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Warrior FAQ</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/faq/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 23:35:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/faq/</guid><description>Lvl70: Single Target vs AoE (Two Targets)?
TL;DR: Very equal, but lvl70 ST wins by a small margin
How do I relic?
Cap Crit, cap Det Check if you can replace any SkS melds in your gear with Det Get any missing SkS through relic Fill the rest of the relic with TNC How do I Upheaval?
All the time. I&amp;rsquo;m using Inner Release&amp;rsquo;s recast timer as a visual guide whether to hit Upheaval or not.</description></item><item><title>Warrior Best in Slot (BiS)</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/best-in-slot/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 23:35:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/best-in-slot/</guid><description>What is the BiS for Ultimates? UCoB / UWU / TEA ? Sets are currently being gathered in one doc: http://bit.ly/WARultimateBIS
Many pieces of gear are BiS when synced down.
The &amp;lsquo;low&amp;rsquo; stat on the higher ilvl gear will reach the stat cap on the lower ilvl gear.
This outweighs the melds you lose in some cases, and in others it is few points of stats behind.
UCoB: ilvl 418 and above will have both stats capped UWU: ilvl 470 and above will have both stats capped TEA: No available ilvl cap yet, syncing gear will not cap all substats and will ignore melding slots.</description></item><item><title>Warrior Stat Priority</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/stat-priority/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 23:35:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/stat-priority/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Warrior Leveling Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/leveling-guide/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 23:32:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/leveling-guide/</guid><description>Henlo team!
We heard you needed some pointers on how to play WAR while leveling. The splits below are done based on what skills you unlock, and what you should take into account.
Do your job quests every five levels. Upgrade your gear every 2-5 levels. Remember your role actions. Gear We want Strength and Vitality. And Weapon Damage. Lots of Weapon Damage. The marketboard is a good place to pick up some cheap upgrades fast, along with Dungeon/Quest/Tomestone gear.</description></item><item><title>Warrior Openers</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/openers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 07:37:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/openers/</guid><description>Warrior Openers and Rotation Opener Optimization Assumed Timings
Tomahawk starts at -0.70s and the pull starts at 0.00s Party buffs are expected to be up at around 7.80s Skill Speed requirements
&amp;gt;=2.47 or slower for skill-for-skill copy. &amp;lt;=2.45 and faster may move oGCDs slightly. Potion
Potion is expected to cover 12 GCDs at these Skill Speeds. Potion can cover 13 GCDs. Plan accordingly. oGCDs</description></item><item><title>Warrior Advanced Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/advanced-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 18:35:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/advanced-guide/</guid><description>Oops, we don&amp;rsquo;t have that guide yet! Interested in contributing? Keep an eye on the site for additional information, coming soon!</description></item><item><title>Warrior Changes</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/job-changes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 02:51:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/job-changes/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Warrior Skills Overview</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/skills-overview/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 08:05:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/skills-overview/</guid><description>Warrior Skills Overview Abilities will be presented in a tabular format for easy reading.
Single Target Actions Icon Action Abbreviation Level Type Recast Description Heavy Swing HS 1 Weaponskill 2.5 seconds The first action in your main combo. Delivers an attack with a potency of 200. Maim 4 Weaponskill 2.5 seconds The second action in your main combo. Delivers an attack with a combo potency of 280.</description></item><item><title>Warrior Basic Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/basic-guide/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 07:48:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/basic-guide/</guid><description>How to Fell Cleave &amp;ldquo;An Angry Wannabe-Healer Guide&amp;rdquo; Warrior Primer v5.3 Introduction Hello, fellow axe wielders, we are Warruru Bros from The Balance discord:
Mox Xinmagar Glu Kos Sizzy Twintails With this guide, we hope to provide everyone with an in-depth view on one of the FINAL FANTASY XIV tanks, Warrior. As such, this guide is dedicated to people already familiar with the basics of Tank role.</description></item></channel></rss>