<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Warrior on Balance Guides</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/</link><description>Recent content in Warrior on Balance Guides</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 18:35:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Warrior Advanced Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/advanced-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 18:35:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/advanced-guide/</guid><description>Oops, we don&amp;rsquo;t have that guide yet! Interested in contributing? Keep an eye on the site for additional information, coming soon!</description></item><item><title>Warrior Changes</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/job-changes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 02:51:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/job-changes/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Warrior Stat Priority</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/stat-priority/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 08:13:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/stat-priority/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Warrior Openers</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/openers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 08:12:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/openers/</guid><description>Warrior Openers and Rotation Opener Optimization At present, there is only a single worthy opener for Warriors, mainly because we want to get Inner Release on cooldown as soon as possible to maximize its usage, and because we can fit an extra Fell Cleave inside the potion by abusing Inner Release’s +15s Eye extension mechanics.
IC IR IC IC Opener IC IR IC IC opener takes advantage of the potion’s whole duration, landing in three Inner Chaos, two combo finishers, a Fell Cleave and all the important oGCDs.</description></item><item><title>Warrior Skills Overview</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/skills-overview/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 08:05:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/skills-overview/</guid><description>Warrior Skills Overview Abilities will be presented in a tabular format for easy reading.
Single Target Heavy Swing Standard basic attack to initiate both the Storm’s Eye Combo and the Storm’s Path Combo, consisting of Heavy Swing, Maim, Storm’s Eye and Heavy Swing, Maim, Storm’s Path respectively. 200 potency GCD Maim 320 potency if combo’d after Heavy Swing.</description></item><item><title>Warrior Basic Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/basic-guide/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 07:48:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/basic-guide/</guid><description>How to Fell Cleave &amp;ldquo;An Angry Wannabe-Healer Guide&amp;rdquo; Warrior Primer v5.3 Introduction Hello, fellow axe wielders, we are Warruru Bros from The Balance discord:
Mox Xinmagar Glu Kos Sizzy Twintails With this guide, we hope to provide everyone with an in-depth view on one of the FINAL FANTASY XIV tanks, Warrior. As such, this guide is dedicated to people already familiar with the basics of Tank role.</description></item><item><title>Warrior Leveling Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/leveling-guide/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 07:44:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/leveling-guide/</guid><description>Henlo team!
We heard you needed some pointers on how to play WAR while leveling. The splits below are done based on what skills you unlock, and what you should take into account.
Do your job quests every five levels.
Upgrade your gear every 2-5 levels.
Remember your role actions.
Gear We want Strength and Vitality. And Weapon Damage. Lots of Weapon Damage.</description></item><item><title>Warrior FAQ</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/faq/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 07:26:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/faq/</guid><description>Lvl70: Single Target vs AoE (Two Targets)?
TL;DR: Very equal, but lvl70 ST wins by a small margin
How do I relic?
Cap Crit, cap Det Check if you can replace any SkS melds in your gear with Det Get any missing SkS through relic Fill the rest of the relic with TNC How do I Upheaval?
All the time. I&amp;rsquo;m using Inner Release&amp;rsquo;s recast timer as a visual guide whether to hit Upheaval or not.</description></item><item><title>Warrior Best in Slot (BiS)</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/best-in-slot/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 07:17:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/best-in-slot/</guid><description>What is the BiS for Ultimates? UCoB / UWU / TEA ? Sets are currently being gathered in one doc: http://bit.ly/WARultimateBIS
Many pieces of gear are BiS when synced down.
The &amp;lsquo;low&amp;rsquo; stat on the higher ilvl gear will reach the stat cap on the lower ilvl gear.
This outweighs the melds you lose in some cases, and in others it is few points of stats behind.
UCoB: ilvl 418 and above will have both stats capped UWU: ilvl 470 and above will have both stats capped TEA: No available ilvl cap yet, syncing gear will not cap all substats and will ignore melding slots.</description></item></channel></rss>