<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scholar on Balance Guides</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/scholar/</link><description>Recent content in Scholar on Balance Guides</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 22:33:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/scholar/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Scholar Skills Overview</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/scholar/skills-overview/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 22:33:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/scholar/skills-overview/</guid><description>Notable Endwalker Changes Broil IV cast time is reduced to 1.5s base cast time. You can weave one oGCD after it without clipping. Do not use Ruin II for weaving. New skills: Protraction and Expedient Shields apply at the slidecast window. It is now possible to cast Adloquium and immediately use Deployment Tactics, but this is still not recommended because this will clip GCD. Energy Drain no longer restores MP.</description></item><item><title>Scholar Leveling Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/scholar/leveling-guide/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 18:08:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/scholar/leveling-guide/</guid><description>This guide is intended for the casual player looking for advice on how to play Scholar in leveling dungeons. Below, we’ll briefly describe all Scholar actions, grouped by level, and some general guidelines for when to use them. For more detailed ability descriptions, please consult the in-game tooltips or job guide, and if you’d like to learn more about playing and optimizing Scholar, check out our other guides.
Quick Glossary SCH: Scholar CD (Cooldown): The time it takes before you’re able to cast an action again.</description></item><item><title>Scholar Changes</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/scholar/job-changes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 22:09:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/scholar/job-changes/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Scholar Advanced Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/scholar/advanced-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 20:47:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/scholar/advanced-guide/</guid><description>Oops, we don&amp;rsquo;t have that guide yet! Interested in contributing? Keep an eye on the site for additional information, coming soon!</description></item><item><title>Scholar Openers</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/scholar/openers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 00:13:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/scholar/openers/</guid><description>Scholar’s kit has a few select tools whose usage dictates how the rest of the opener operates: namely Dissipation and Chain Stratagem. Where to use these skills optimally is less determined by a Scholar’s own kit - being that the rotation is simply a DoT and Broil - and more so determined by where the rest of the raid is using their own raid buffs to line up with each other’s rotations.</description></item><item><title>Scholar FAQ</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/scholar/faq/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 23:57:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/scholar/faq/</guid><description>Scholar FAQ How can I see my fairy&amp;rsquo;s nameplate in battle?
A. Character Configuration &amp;gt; Control Settings &amp;gt; &amp;ldquo;Target&amp;rdquo; tab &amp;gt; Under &amp;ldquo;Target Settings&amp;rdquo;, Uncheck &amp;ldquo;Disable targeting of pets and minions when in battle.&amp;rdquo;
B. Character Config &amp;gt; Display Name Settings &amp;gt; &amp;ldquo;Own&amp;rdquo; tab &amp;gt; Under &amp;ldquo;Pets&amp;rdquo; set &amp;ldquo;Display Name Settings&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;Always&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;During Battle&amp;rdquo;
Both options must be set this way or your fairy&amp;rsquo;s nameplate will be hidden.</description></item><item><title>Scholar Best in Slot (BiS)</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/scholar/best-in-slot/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 23:41:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/scholar/best-in-slot/</guid><description>SCH BiS and Gear Options 5.55 Savage Sets So, why the hell is SCH BiS 2.32 GCD this tier? The short answer is that our gear absolutely sucks for 2.41 this tier. We either have to take on a bunch of piety or use crafted gear, and neither one is efficient. 2.32 GCD lines up AF well, but sits on a sort of halfway point of DoT timings that requires us to alternate between 12 GCD and 13 GCD Bios, which can result in lost Bio ticks.</description></item><item><title>Scholar Stat Priority</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/scholar/stat-priority/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 23:38:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/scholar/stat-priority/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Scholar Basic Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/scholar/basic-guide/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 21:33:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/scholar/basic-guide/</guid><description>Indomitable, A Thorough Guide to Scholar Author Tobio Okuma
This is a guide for the Scholar (SCH) Job in FFXIV. The goal of this guide is to give insight into how the job is operating in our current raid environment. I will go over all of the job’s skills and describe their usage, as well as break down how Scholar interacts with other healers. I will go through small optimizations, useful macros, and more.</description></item></channel></rss>