<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Astrologian on Balance Guides</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/astrologian/</link><description>Recent content in Astrologian on Balance Guides</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 21:43:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/astrologian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Astrologian Openers</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/astrologian/openers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 21:43:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/astrologian/openers/</guid><description>Opener The most up to date Astrologian opener(s) can always be found in the #ast_resources channel on The Balance Discord. Keep in mind that Astrologian openers are extremely flexible and depend almost entirely on the circumstances of the fight, the timings of the planned raid DPS bursts, and party composition. Any premade Astrologian opener is a generic framework, not a universally optimal opener.
We&amp;rsquo;ve taken a lot of care to evaluate as many of the variables as we reasonably can and identify the core methodology of the most statistically successful opener with regard to when most DPS jobs burst the hardest and when other raid buffs should be coming out, assuming everyone is doing a proper opener.</description></item><item><title>Astrologian Leveling Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/astrologian/leveling-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 06:25:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/astrologian/leveling-guide/</guid><description>Introduction This guide is intended to help you level Astrologian to level 90 from any given starting point, while also beginning to slowly suggest fundamental strategies and techniques. Habits develop early, and practice makes permanent.
This guide is not intended to be a complete guide on how to heal in dungeons, trials, or any other content. However, the following section is intended to give some strategies to the mindset of a healer in XIV, and I recommend you read it if you have never been a healer in specifically XIV-related max-level content before.</description></item><item><title>Astrologian FAQ</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/astrologian/faq/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 05:39:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/astrologian/faq/</guid><description>What Sect Should I Use? Diurnal remains generally very efficient, but buffs to Celestial Opposition and Celestial Intersection reduce the reliance on GCD healing (which is where Nocturnal Sect primarily falls short of Diurnal), and Nocturnal Intersection is very strong. The gap in overall efficiency between Diurnal and Nocturnal Sect is still quite significant, but that shouldn&amp;rsquo;t put you off of using Nocturnal Sect when the situation calls for it.</description></item><item><title>Astrologian Best in Slot (BiS)</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/astrologian/best-in-slot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 05:32:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/astrologian/best-in-slot/</guid><description>5.5 AST BiS SETS https://bit.ly/astgearcalc
So we&amp;rsquo;re here, finally with a proper writeup.
Making BiS was expected to be very difficult this tier with AST&amp;rsquo;s new affinity for SpS&amp;hellip;but instead it actually was quite easy. Avoid Piety like the plague and there you go, there&amp;rsquo;s your BiS pieces.
Higher Piety sets also have the nice consolation of having a wealth of Crit (rather than the traditional disgusting amounts of Det) so it won&amp;rsquo;t even feel that bad to swap to lower damage for the sake of Piety.</description></item><item><title>Astrologian Changes</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/astrologian/job-changes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 03:46:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/astrologian/job-changes/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Astrologian Stat Priority</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/astrologian/stat-priority/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 21:17:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/astrologian/stat-priority/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Astrologian Advanced Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/astrologian/advanced-guide/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 21:00:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/astrologian/advanced-guide/</guid><description>So, you&amp;rsquo;re (hopefully) comfortable with the fundamentals of Astrologian. Now, it’s time to talk details: quirky mechanics, important interactions, and optimization. We’ll start with the most straightforward topics and work up to the more complicated ones.
Sect Swapping/Stance Dancing In dungeons, you can swap to Nocturnal Sect after the last enemy in a pull dies, apply a shield to the tank in preparation for the next pull, and then swap back to Diurnal Sect.</description></item><item><title>Astrologian Skills Overview</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/astrologian/skills-overview/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 20:48:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/astrologian/skills-overview/</guid><description>Actions Icon Action Level Type MP Casting Recast Description Malefic 1 Spell 400 1.5s 2.5s Deals unaspected damage with a potency of 150. Benefic 2 Spell 400 1.5s 2.5s Restores target&amp;rsquo;s HP. Combust 4 Spell 400 Instant 2.5s Deals unaspected damage over time. Lightspeed 6 Ability Instant 90s Reduces cast times for spells by 2.</description></item><item><title>Astrologian Basic Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/astrologian/basic-guide/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 19:26:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/astrologian/basic-guide/</guid><description>Intro to Astrologian Who Needs MP When You’re This Pretty? Brought to you by Zyrkhan Dar’locke, AKA Literally Who
No, we still can’t be Gambit
The Scope of this Guide As the title implies, this guide is intended to function as an introduction to Astrologian. This guide is concerned with Astrologian only. It will not address the general principles of healing as they apply to all healers. Those things are discussed in Zyrk’s Bullshit Guide to the Principles of Healing.</description></item></channel></rss>