<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>White Mage on Balance Guides</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/healers/white-mage/</link><description>Recent content in White Mage on Balance Guides</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 03:54:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/healers/white-mage/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>White Mage Changes</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/healers/white-mage/job-changes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 03:54:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/healers/white-mage/job-changes/</guid><description/></item><item><title>White Mage Leveling Guide</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/healers/white-mage/leveling-guide/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Oct 2021 03:45:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/healers/white-mage/leveling-guide/</guid><description>The Walter White Mage Leveling Guide Written by Eva Izunia (Goblin) Leveling White Mage allows you access to some of the smoothest dungeon runs in the game, due to the supremely high damage output when crowd controlling enemy groups and the nature of the job in general.
But to get there, you first must begin on the road.
Unlocking White Mage is done upon reaching level 30 with the Conjurer class and completing the quest Seer Folly after completing the MSQ quest Sylph-management.</description></item><item><title>White Mage Basic Guide</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/healers/white-mage/basic-guide/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 03:52:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/healers/white-mage/basic-guide/</guid><description>Hi there, I’m pyre and this is my long overdue guide to White Mage in Shadowbringers, one month before Endwalker release… Luckily, based on current information from the Endwalker Media Tour, most of this information will carry into Endwalker, though I will update it shortly after release. This will be a fairly short and straightforward guide that addresses the basics of WHM mechanics and play, and will be expanded upon in Endwalker.</description></item><item><title>White Mage Openers</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/healers/white-mage/openers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 01:10:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/healers/white-mage/openers/</guid><description>Standard Opener In most cases, use this:
PRE-PULL
-3.5s Tincture
-2.5s Glare
PULL
Dia + Assize + Presence of Mind
Glare
Glare
Glare
Glare
(etc.)
&amp;ldquo;I Need An Extra oGCD&amp;rdquo; Opener PRE-PULL
-3.5s Tincture
-2.5s Glare
PULL
Dia + Assize + Swiftcast
Glare + Temperance + Presence of Mind
Glare
Glare
Glare
Glare
(etc.)
(Temperance can be swapped with any needed oGCD).
GCD Rotation Planner Looking for an advanced tool to plan out your rotation for a fight, compare openers, etc.</description></item><item><title>White Mage Skills Overview</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/healers/white-mage/skills-overview/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 00:58:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/healers/white-mage/skills-overview/</guid><description>Actions Icon Action Level Type MP Casting Recast Description Stone 1 Spell 400 2.5s 2.5s Deals earth damage with a potency of 140. Cure 2 Spell 400 1.5s 2.5s Restores target&amp;rsquo;s HP with a potency of 450. Aero 4 Spell 400 Instant 2.5s Deals wind damage with a potency of 50. Additionally deals wind damage over time with a potency of 30 for 18s.</description></item><item><title>White Mage Stat Priority</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/healers/white-mage/stat-priority/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 00:54:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/healers/white-mage/stat-priority/</guid><description/></item><item><title>White Mage FAQ</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/healers/white-mage/faq/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 00:50:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/healers/white-mage/faq/</guid><description>White Mage FAQ How should movement and weaving be handled? White Mage (WHM) is one of the least mobile jobs in the game, and so planning movement is critical to success. Below is a list of available options; keep in mind that it’s heavily subjective based on the encounter and your party.
Pre-position with slidecasts and natural Dia refreshes Natural Dia refresh (&amp;lt; ~3s remaining), slidecast, or Swiftcast + Glare (not clipped, always consider holding for raise in prog) Rapture that does useful healing, Misery Regen that does necessary healing (rare in Savage and below) Overheal Lilies Dia outside natural refresh (almost always avoidable) Extended movements involve a combination of these roughly in order of priority, and a lot of movement can be minimized with proper prepositioning utilizing a combination of Dia and slidecasting.</description></item><item><title>White Mage Best in Slot (BiS)</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/healers/white-mage/best-in-slot/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 00:17:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/healers/white-mage/best-in-slot/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>