<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Bard on Balance Guides</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/bard/</link><description>Recent content in Bard on Balance Guides</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 03:10:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/bard/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Black Mage Changes</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/bard/job-changes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 03:10:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/bard/job-changes/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Bard Stat Priority</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/bard/stat-priority/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 02:42:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/bard/stat-priority/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Bard Best in Slot (BiS)</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/bard/best-in-slot/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 02:40:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/bard/best-in-slot/</guid><description>5.5x Best In Slot BiS with Relic: https://etro.gg/gearset/8418d22e-d70e-4b1a-87e0-d2b79dc3bd91
BiS, no Relic: https://etro.gg/gearset/865fc886-994f-4c28-8fc1-4379f160a916
2.50 BiS for high ping (relic): https://etro.gg/gearset/6e8892d6-68b0-4597-ba17-1efdc0e62084
2.50s BiS for high ping (no relic): https://etro.gg/gearset/cac58997-d0d5-4e92-b6fd-a131e8a775e2
TEA Best In Slot: Relic 2.44s: https://etro.gg/gearset/1081f33f-8c37-4ef4-b569-30e30092174f
Relic 2.47s: https://etro.gg/gearset/f0eafbaf-fb74-48ee-99a8-21780ff8a793
(These are basically equal, pick to taste.)
No-relic 2.44s: https://etro.gg/gearset/c4e0a8ce-e69e-4efc-8971-f4ae5d4c5918
For level 70 Ultimates: Any gear that&amp;rsquo;s i470 or higher will suffice, as it syncs down to maximum substats for UWU. You can get some bonus value out of a 515/535 relic by keeping its substats at 318/280 or less (for UWU/UCoB).</description></item><item><title>Bard Advanced Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/bard/advanced-guide/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 02:37:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/bard/advanced-guide/</guid><description>From the full BRD guide, located here.
RS Alignment Choice After the opener (i.e. starting from the second RS), you can elect to either align RS with the beginning of WM or the end. The tradeoff is that WM tends to have back-loaded damage, but Army’s Muse makes it easier to deal nine GCDs under RS.
Aligning RS with the beginning of WM is the easiest choice, but is slightly worse for damage.</description></item><item><title>Bard FAQ</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/bard/faq/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 02:31:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/bard/faq/</guid><description>Single target FAQ When should I use Raging Strikes after the opener?
A couple of GCDs into Minuet. This is to cover as much Pitch Perfect potential as possible.
When do I use my second/third potion?
Try to cover Raging Strikes and Barrage with it. That damage spike is bigger than any heap of party buffs. If you can, also try to pop it right before an Iron Jaws, so that you can IJ at the end and get two runs of buffed DoTs.</description></item><item><title>Bard Openers</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/bard/openers/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 02:30:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/bard/openers/</guid><description>Bard Openers For all openers;
Use Pitch Perfect at three stacks as able, and Refulgent procs as you get them. Hold Barrage until the next GCD if you already have an Refulgent proc. The best potion is high-quality Grade 4 Tincture of Dexterity. Try to use your second oGCD in the normal-ping openers as late as you can without cutting into your next GCD. 2.44s to 2.47s GCD 2.</description></item><item><title>Bard Skills Overview</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/bard/skills-overview/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 02:24:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/bard/skills-overview/</guid><description>Tooltips here are rewritten from the official translations to clarify some portions that aren’t obvious in the official job guide.
GCDs Burst Shot (BS) Delivers an attack with a potency of 250. Additional Effect: 35% chance of becoming Straight Shot Ready for 10s. Refulgent Arrow (RA) Delivers an attack with a potency of 340. Can only be executed when Straight Shot Ready.</description></item><item><title>Bard Basic Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/bard/basic-guide/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 02:17:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/bard/basic-guide/</guid><description>Authors by Verzell Varion [Adamantoise] with contributions from Im’hotep Rah [Goblin], Sana Cetonis [Sargatanas], Ellunavi Sevald [Sargatanas], Yumiya Nagatsuki [Behemoth], Elya Kura [Ragnarok]
Foreword Hi all! Welcome to our Bard guide, freshly revamped for the 5.x Shadowbringers expansion. This guide will cover concepts of Bard gameplay, from the very fundamentals to the limits of optimization, as well as serving as a pocket reference for all aspects of Bard.
With the launch of Shadowbringers, Bard received changes that didn’t compromise its core identity nor feel of gameplay, but were still substantial enough to deserve major guide revisions.</description></item><item><title>Bard Leveling Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/bard/leveling-guide/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 02:14:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/bard/leveling-guide/</guid><description>A Guide For Bards That Aren’t Level 80 Yet While the main Balance guide is focused on level 80 gameplay, I thought it’d be nice to have something people can follow as they level.
Leveling content may not be tough enough to really need to optimize, but it’s still nice to not feel completely lost.
So, here are some general outlines for various level ranges, and tips for what skills are going to bring the biggest changes.</description></item></channel></rss>