<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Samurai on Balance Guides</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/samurai/</link><description>Recent content in Samurai on Balance Guides</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 03:43:49 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/samurai/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Samurai Changes</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/samurai/job-changes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 03:43:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/samurai/job-changes/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Samurai Stat Priority</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/samurai/stat-priority/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 03:33:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/samurai/stat-priority/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Samurai Best in Slot (BiS)</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/samurai/best-in-slot/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 03:29:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/samurai/best-in-slot/</guid><description>Samurai Savage Best In Slot: 2.14 GCD Relic &amp;lsquo;slowSam&amp;rsquo; BiS - [23,201 DPS] Etro
2.14 GCD OLD &amp;lsquo;slowSam&amp;rsquo; BiS - [23,029 DPS] Etro
28 GCD loop, two filler GCDs, most used sets. Play these.
2.07 GCD Relic &amp;lsquo;flexSam&amp;rsquo; BiS - [23,102 DPS] Etro
2.07 GCD OLD &amp;lsquo;flexSam&amp;rsquo; BiS - [22,933 DPS] Etro
29 GCD loop, three filler GCDs, beginner friendly due to Gekko/Kasha filler, can only iai-weave on ping ≤ 10ms without clipping.</description></item><item><title>Samurai Advanced Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/samurai/advanced-guide/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 03:28:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/samurai/advanced-guide/</guid><description>The Shadowbringers Samurai Compendium An Exploration of 5.0 Samurai Mechanics By Jahaudant @ The Balance &amp;amp; DPS Tools Discords Last Updated 17th April 2020
Introduction Final Fantasy XIV Version 5.0: Shadowbringers has arrived, and with it a plethora of job and balance changes for Samurai &amp;ndash; many of which have significant implications on how we should be playing the job optimally.
Before we get started, it is important to note that this document is not intended to act as a traditional guide.</description></item><item><title>Samurai FAQ</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/samurai/faq/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 03:27:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/samurai/faq/</guid><description>Is X better than Y for me?
For weapons: item level (ilvl)/weapon damage (wd) wins, regardless of substats. For armor: ilvl usually wins, unless 5 materia slots. For same-ilvl pieces: substat itemization can be in your favor or not depending on the rest of your gear and stat tiering. When in doubt, use the Gear Planner - only here can you get an accurate answer for your setup!</description></item><item><title>Samurai Openers</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/samurai/openers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 03:26:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/samurai/openers/</guid><description>Samurai Standard Openers: Higanbana First: Standard
Single Weave
Video Example
Your standard opener which, due to the earlier DoT application, is ahead in output for the majority of any given encounter.
Midare First: Standard
Single Weave
Video Example
Should be reserved for encounters with a phase or kill time such that you are able to land an additional Midare/Tsubame where Higanbana first would not.
Samurai Non-Standard Openers: Alternative Higanbana First: Standard</description></item><item><title>Samurai Skills Overview</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/samurai/skills-overview/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 03:24:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/samurai/skills-overview/</guid><description>Actions Weaponskills (GCD) Hakaze Single target combo starter. 200 potency. +5 Kenki. Jinpu Single target second step combo. 100 potency, 320 potency if combo from Hakaze. Combo Bonus: Increases damage dealt by 13% for 40s, +5 Kenki. Shifu Single target second step combo. 100 potency, 320 potency if combo from Hakaze.</description></item><item><title>Samurai Basic Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/samurai/basic-guide/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 03:18:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/samurai/basic-guide/</guid><description>Updated by Sweaty Boxer of Midgardsormr
FFXIV: Shadowbringers Patch 5.25, April 2020 With thanks to members of the Balance Discord for discussion and theorycrafting (Jahudant and Boxer) Images and icons are properties of Square Enix Foreword With the release of Shadowbringers, Samurai is now celebrating two years in the game, and with Aureum’s permission I’m taking over as caretaker for this guide. The 5.0 update brings with it several changes to both Samurai and melee as a whole, but due to the nature of this guide, I will be introducing them for players new to the job.</description></item><item><title>Samurai Leveling Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/samurai/leveling-guide/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 03:18:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/samurai/leveling-guide/</guid><description>Level 50 Level 50 Opener
Keep buffs up, reapply your Higanbana as close to zero as possible, Midare goes brrrrrr.
Level 52 You learn Kenki Mastery I, which introduces the Kenki gauge and positionals on Gekko/Kasha. Use Kaiten exclusively on Iaijutsu (Higanbana &amp;gt; Midare).
Level 60 Level 60 Opener
Use the above and read Level 52 for the rest.
Level 62 You learn Kenki Mastery II. Begin to Kaiten all Iaijutsu, use excess Kenki on Shinten, use Level 70 Openers.</description></item></channel></rss>