<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Samurai on Balance Guides</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/samurai/</link><description>Recent content in Samurai on Balance Guides</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 00:20:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/samurai/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Samurai Changes</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/samurai/job-changes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 00:20:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/samurai/job-changes/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Samurai Basic Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/samurai/basic-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 22:59:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/samurai/basic-guide/</guid><description>Updated by Zombii (Alice Quates of Faerie) and Sweaty Boxer of Midgardsormr .
With thanks to members of the Balance Discord for discussion and theorycrafting (Jahudant and Boxer)
Images and icons are properties of Square Enix.
Foreword With the release of Endwalker, Samurai is now celebrating four years in the game. With Boxer’s permission, I’m updating this guide for Endwalker. 6.0 doesn’t change a whole lot about the fundamentals of playing Samurai or melee, but this guide is still intended for newer players.</description></item><item><title>Samurai Stat Priority</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/samurai/stat-priority/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 06:02:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/samurai/stat-priority/</guid><description>Based on current gear available to us, if you&amp;rsquo;re not using the Gear Planner to figure out what melds are best for your specific situation the below is a decent blind meld order to follow: SKS (to tier)* &amp;gt; Crit &amp;gt; Det &amp;gt;= DH
Check out the Gear Planner here.
*To one of the recommended SkS ranges.\
Viable GCD/SkS ranges (with Shifu counted) for looping:\
Recast with Shifu SkS Range Filler Req.</description></item><item><title>Samurai Best in Slot (BiS)</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/samurai/best-in-slot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 05:56:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/samurai/best-in-slot/</guid><description>Samurai Savage Best In Slot: 2.14 GCD Relic &amp;lsquo;slowSam&amp;rsquo; BiS - [23,201 DPS] Etro
2.14 GCD OLD &amp;lsquo;slowSam&amp;rsquo; BiS - [23,029 DPS] Etro
28 GCD loop, two filler GCDs, most used sets. Play these.
2.07 GCD Relic &amp;lsquo;flexSam&amp;rsquo; BiS - [23,102 DPS] Etro
2.07 GCD OLD &amp;lsquo;flexSam&amp;rsquo; BiS - [22,933 DPS] Etro
29 GCD loop, three filler GCDs, beginner friendly due to Gekko/Kasha filler, can only iai-weave on ping ≤ 10ms without clipping.</description></item><item><title>Samurai Openers</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/samurai/openers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 05:53:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/samurai/openers/</guid><description>Your standard opener which will be used in the majority of encounters. Due to phasing, in some instances it may be best to begin with Kasha into Gekko instead.
If Iai weaves are easier than double weaves for you, feel free to move Senei forward before Kaeshi: Setsugekka.</description></item><item><title>Samurai Skills Overview</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/samurai/skills-overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 21:56:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/samurai/skills-overview/</guid><description>Samurai Skills Overview Global Cooldown Actions (Single Target) Icon Name Description Hakaze Single target combo starter. 150 potency. +5 Kenki. Jinpu Single target second step combo. 100 potency, 250 potency if combo from Hakaze. Combo Bonus: Fugetsu buff (increased damage dealt by 13% for 40s), +5 Kenki. Shifu Single target second step combo.</description></item><item><title>Samurai Advanced Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/samurai/advanced-guide/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 03:28:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/samurai/advanced-guide/</guid><description>The Shadowbringers Samurai Compendium An Exploration of 5.0 Samurai Mechanics By Jahaudant @ The Balance &amp;amp; DPS Tools Discords Last Updated 17th April 2020
Introduction Final Fantasy XIV Version 5.0: Shadowbringers has arrived, and with it a plethora of job and balance changes for Samurai &amp;ndash; many of which have significant implications on how we should be playing the job optimally.
Before we get started, it is important to note that this document is not intended to act as a traditional guide.</description></item><item><title>Samurai FAQ</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/samurai/faq/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 03:27:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/samurai/faq/</guid><description>Is X better than Y for me?
For weapons: item level (ilvl)/weapon damage (wd) wins, regardless of substats. For armor: ilvl usually wins, unless 5 materia slots. For same-ilvl pieces: substat itemization can be in your favor or not depending on the rest of your gear and stat tiering. When in doubt, use the Gear Planner - only here can you get an accurate answer for your setup!</description></item><item><title>Samurai Leveling Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/samurai/leveling-guide/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 03:18:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/samurai/leveling-guide/</guid><description>Level 50 Level 50 Opener
Keep buffs up, reapply your Higanbana as close to zero as possible, Midare goes brrrrrr.
Level 52 You learn Kenki Mastery I, which introduces the Kenki gauge and positionals on Gekko/Kasha. Use Kaiten exclusively on Iaijutsu (Higanbana &amp;gt; Midare).
Level 60 Level 60 Opener
Use the above and read Level 52 for the rest.
Level 62 You learn Kenki Mastery II. Begin to Kaiten all Iaijutsu, use excess Kenki on Shinten, use Level 70 Openers.</description></item></channel></rss>